The Duggan Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 3. Duggan Family Personal Papers, 1928 - 2004; 3; Box: 10 Folders: 1 - 41
  - Biographical Documents, 1969 - 1996; 3.1; Box: 10 Folders: 1 - 8
    - Twenty years ago, circa 1990 (Folder 8, Box 10)
  - Personal papers of Stephen P. Duggan, Jr., 1928 - 1981; 3.2; Box: 10 Folders: 9 - 22
    - Bully For You Steve Duggan Party invitation, 1981 (Folder 9, Box 10)
    - The Century Club, 1942 - 1998 (Folder 10, Box 10)
    - Columbia University Law Alumni Bulletin (Stephen P. Duggan, President), 1968 - 1969 (Folder 11, Box 10)
    - Correspondence concerning Stephen P. Duggan, Jr.'s resignation from the NRDC, 1980 (Folder 12, Box 10)
    - Correspondence with James Cope, 1966 (Folder 13, Box 10)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. Carl S. Row, 1966 (Folder 14, Box 10)
    - Correspondence with Durand H. Van Doren, 1965 (Folder 15, Box 10)
    - Good-Bye, England by Stephen P. Duggan, (Sr.) Ph.D, LL.D, circa 1928 (Folder 16, Box 10)
    - Correspondence with Thad Horton, Headmaster of Storm King School, undated (Folder 17, Box 10)
    - Mock Lawsuit, undated (Folder 18, Box 10)
    - Mountain Madness or the Peak of Perfection: A Celebration of Stephen P. Duggan (Jr.), undated (Folder 19, Box 10)
    - Notebook of Books, circa 1960 (Folder 20, Box 10)
    - Tribute to Mr. Stephen P. Duggan, Jr. by Mr. Wilkie upon his retirement from the Vassar College Board of Trustees, 1970 (Folder 21, Box 10)
    - Tribute to Mr. Wilkie by Mr. Stephen P. Duggan, Jr. upon his retirement as Chairman of the Board of Trustees of Vassar College, 1969 (Folder 22, Box 10)
  - Family Papers, 1958 - 2004; 3.3; Box: 10 Folders: 23 - 33
    - Correspondence concerning the death of Stephen P. Duggan, Sr., 1950 (Folder 23, Box 10)
    - Correspondence pertaining to the death Beatrice Abbott Smokey Duggan, 1996 (Folder 24, Box 10)
    - Correspondence regarding the death of Stephen P. Duggan, Jr., 1998 (Folder 25, Box 10)
    - Letter regarding the Duggan family, undated (Folder 26, Box 10)
    - Letter remembering Stephen P. Duggan, Jr. and Beatrice Abbott Smokey Duggan, 2004 (Folder 27, Box 10)
    - Note from Mary Vance Duggan to Stephen P. Duggan, Jr., circa 1976 (Folder 28, Box 10)
    - Playbill featuring S. P. (Stephen Pierce) Duggan, Jr., circa 1958 (Folder 29, Box 10)
    - Statement of ENS. P. M. (Peter Mathiessen) Duggan, USNR, Boat Officer Rescue Detail, USS William V. Pratt regarding the crash of an F3 aircraft from the USS Shangri-La on 4 March 1964 (Folder 30, Box 10)
  - Famous Correspondence, 1967 - 1983; 3.4; Box: 10 Folders: 31 - 35
    By person
    - Louis S. Auchincloss, 1978 (Folder 31, Box 10)
    - Jimmy Carter Administration, 1976 - 1980 (Folder 32, Box 10)
    - Theodore R. Kupferman, 1967 (Folder 33, Box 10)
    - Amos Melamede, 1983 (Folder 34, Box 10)
    - John B. Oakes, 1977 (Folder 35, Box 10)
  - Miscellany, 1975 - 2008; 3.5; Box: 10 Folders: 36 - 41
    - Clipping quote of Theodore Roosevelt and William Howard Taft, undated (Folder 36, Box 10)
    - The Despairing Optimist, No. 22, 1975 (Folder 37, Box 10)
    - Literature, undated (Folder 38, Box 10)
    - Painting of Hudson River scenes, undated (Folder 39, Box 10)
    - Premiere ticket: All the President's Men, 1976 (Folder 40, Box 10)
    - Wedding program of Laura Susan Robert and Stewart Campbell Clay (Peter Mathiessen Duggan, groomsman), 2008 (Folder 41, Box 10)
- 4. Clippings, 1944 - 2007; 4; Boxes: 10 - 13 Folders: 42 - 51, 1 - 35, 1 - 45, 1 - 4
  Series contains clippings concerning Storm King, NRDC, the Duggan family, and other clippings found in the collection
  - Clippings Concerning Storm King, 1964 - 1988; 4.1; Boxes: 10 - 11 Folders: 42 - 51, 1 - 21
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 1, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 2, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 3, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 4, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 5, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 6, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 7, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 8, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1966 (Folder 9, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1966 (Folder 10, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Folder 11, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Folder 12, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Folder 13, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Folder 14, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1968 (Folder 15, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1973 (Folder 16, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1988 (Folder 17, Box 11)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 18, Box 11)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 19, Box 11)
    - Bound clippings - originals, circa 1965 (Folder 20, Box 11)
    - Bound clippings - preserved, circa 1965 (Folder 21, Box 11)
  - Clippings Concerning NRDC, 1976 - 1980; 4.2; Box: 11 Folders: 22 - 28
    - Clippings, 1976 (Folder 22, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1977 (Folder 23, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1982 (Folder 24, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1984 (Folder 25, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1987 (Folder 26, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1990 (Folder 27, Box 11)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 28, Box 11)
  - Clippings Concerning the Duggan family, 1944 - 1998; 4.3; Box: 11 Folders: 29 - 35
    - Clippings, 1944 (Folder 29, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1966 (Folder 30, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1968 (Folder 31, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1981 (Folder 32, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1993 (Folder 33, Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1998 (Folder 34, Box 11)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 35, Box 11)
    - Clippings Found in Envelope, 1942 - 1960; 4.3.1; Boxes: 12 Folders: 1 - 10
      - Envelope, 1960 (Folder 1, Box 12)
      - Document, 1942 (Folder 2, Box 12)
      - Document, undated (Folder 3, Box 12)
      - Reviews of A Professor at Large by Stephen Duggan (New York: The Macmillan Company, 1943), 1943 - 1944 (Folder 4, Box 12)
      - Reviews of The Americas: The Search for Hemispheric Security by Laurence Duggan (New York: Henry Holt and Co., 1949) (Folder 5, Box 12)
      - Poems, undated (Folder 6, Box 12)
      - Poems, undated (Folder 7, Box 12)
      - Poems, undated (Folder 8, Box 12)
      - Poems, undated (Folder 9, Box 12)
      - Poems, undated (Folder 10, Box 12)
  - Topical Clippings, 1989; 4.4; Box: 12 Folders: 11 - 38
    Alphabetical by subject
    - Atmospheric Protection Initiative - originals, 1989 (Folder 11, Box 12)
    - Atmospheric Protection Initiative - preserved, 1989 (Folder 12, Box 12)
    - Agriculture and Forestry - originals, 1989 (Folder 13, Box 12)
    - Agriculture and Forestry - preserved, 1989 (Folder 14, Box 12)
    - Clean Air - originals, 1989 (Folder 15, Box 12)
    - Clean Air - preserved, 1989 (Folder 16, Box 12)
    - Clean Water - originals, 1989 (Folder 17, Box 12)
    - Clean Water - preserved, 1989 (Folder 18, Box 12)
    - Coastal - originals, 1989 (Folder 19, Box 12)
    - Coastal - preserved, 1989 (Folder 20, Box 12)
    - Energy - originals, 1989 (Folder 21, Box 12)
    - Energy - preserved, 1989 (Folder 22, Box 12)
    - International - originals, 1989 (Folder 23, Box 12)
    - International - preserved, 1989 (Folder 24, Box 12)
    - General - originals, 1989 (Folder 25, Box 12)
    - General - preserved, 1989 (Folder 26, Box 12)
    - Los Angeles Office - originals, 1989 (Folder 27, Box 12)
    - Los Angeles Office - preserved, 1989 (Folder 28, Box 12)
    - Nuclear - originals, 1989 (Folder 29, Box 12)
    - Nuclear - preserved, 1989 (Folder 30, Box 12)
    - Pesticides including mothers and others - originals, 1989 (Folder 31, Box 12)
    - Pesticides including mothers and others - preserved, 1989 (Folder 32, Box 12)
    - Toxics - originals, 1989 (Folder 33, Box 12)
    - Toxics - preserved, 1989 (Folder 34, Box 12)
    - Urban Environment - originals, 1989 (Folder 35, Box 12)
    - Urban Environment - preserved, 1989 (Folder 36, Box 12)
    - Western Water - originals, 1989 (Folder 37, Box 12)
    - Western Water - preserved, 1989 (Folder 38, Box 12)
  - Clippings found elsewhere in the collection, 1963 - 1982; 4.5; Box: 12 Folders: 39 - 45
    - Clippings, 1963 (Folder 39, Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 40, Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 41, Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1966 (Folder 42, Box 12)
    - Clippings, circa 1960s (Folder 43, Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1982 (Folder 44, Box 12)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 45, Box 12)
  - Miscellany, 1997 - 2007; 4.6; Box: 13 Folders: 1 - 4
    - Clippings, 1977 (Folder 1, Box 13)
    - Clippings, 2005 (Folder 2, Box 13)
    - Clippings, 2007 (Folder 3, Box 13)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 4, Box 13)
- 5. Books and Pamphlets, 1973 - 1994; 5; Boxes: 13 Folders: 5 - 13
  - World Directory of Environmental Education Programs, ed. Philip W. Quigg (New York; London: R.R. Bowker Company - A Xerox Education Company, 1973) (Folder 5, Box 13)
  - The Dilemma Facing Humanity: International Symposium I May 1974 (Battelle) (Folder 6, Box 13)
  - Progress: As If Survival Mattered, ed. Hugh Nash (San Francisco: Friends of the Earth, 1977) (Folder 7, Box 13)
  - Country Lawyer, by Bellamy Partridge (1939; reprint. Albany, NY: Charles Evans Hughes Press, 1979) (Folder 8, Box 13)
  - The Fight to Save Wild Alaska, by Robert Cahn, 1980 (Folder 9, Box 13)
  - Moving California Toward A Renewable Energy Future: An Alternative Scenario for the Next Fifteen Years, by Laura B. King with others (San Francisco: Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc., 1980) (Folder 10, Box 13)
  - Missile Envy: The Arms Race and Nuclear War, by Dr. Helen Caldicott (1984; reprint. Toronto; New York; London; Sydney; Auckland: Bantam Books, 1986) (Folder 11, Box 13)
  - Cornwall, New York: Images from the Past, 1788-1920, by Janet Dempsey with others (Friends of the Cornwall Public Library, 1988) (Folder 12, Box 13)
  - Rand McNally Quick Reference World Atlas (Rand McNally and Company, 1994) (Folder 13, Box 13)
- 6. Graphic Materials, 1964 - 1979; 6; Boxes: 13 - 14 Folders: 14 - 41, 1 - 8
  Series contains family photographs, images concerning Hudson River conservation, miscellany, and film negvatives
  By subject and type
  - Family Photographs, 6.1; linear feet Box: 13 Folder: 14
    - Family photographs, [3 images], undated (Folder 14, Box 13)
  - Images Concerning Hudson River Conservation, 1964 - 1978; 6.2; linear feet Boxes: 13 - 14 Folders: 15 - 41, 1 - 4
    - Photographic print of William Livingston Meiser Reese with Woman, undated (Folder 15, Box 13)
    - Photographic print of Storm King Mountain with proposed plant, circa 1960s (Folder 16, Box 13)
    - Photographic prints concerning Hudson River conservation, 1964 - 1978 (Folder 17, Box 13)
    - Storm King Mountain, [5 sheets], undated (Folder 18, Box 13)
    - Storm King Mountain, [5 sheets], undated (Folder 19, Box 13)
    - Storm King Mountain, [5 sheets], undated (Folder 20, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 21, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 22, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 23, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 24, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 25, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 26, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 27, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 28, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 29, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 30, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 31, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 32, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 33, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 34, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 35, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 36, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 37, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 38, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 39, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 40, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 41, Box 13)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 1, Box 14)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 2, Box 14)
    - Contact sheets, [5 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 3, Box 14)
    - Contact sheets, [4 sheets], circa 1960s (Folder 4, Box 14)
  - Miscellany, 1966 - 1979; 6.3; Box: 14 Folders: 5 - 6
    Series contains ampitheater dedication, information from meeting with Jimmy Carter
    - Ampitheater dedication, United States Military Academy, West Point, NY [sic], 1966 (Folder 5, Box 14)
    - Environmental organization meeting with President Jimmy Carter, 1979 (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - Film Negatives, 6.4; Box: 14 Folders: 7 - 8
    - Bear Mountain Hearings negatives, Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, [20 images], undated (Folder 7, Box 14)
    - Film negatives, subject unknown [28 images], undated (Folder 8, Box 14)
- 7. Documents concerning the screenplay written by Mary Vance Duggan, 1999 - 2008; 7; linear feet Boxes: 14 - 15 Folders: 9 - 14, 1 - 28
  Series contains Completed Screenplays, Genealogical Research, Research done by Mary Vance Duggan, and Writing Notes and Drafts
  Subseries are seperated by subject, some are arrangeed chronologically
  - Completed Screenplays, 7.1; Box: 14 Folders: 9 - 14
    - In the Public Interest, by Mary Vance Duggan, 2005 (Folder 9, Box 14)
    - In the Public Interest, by Mary Vance Duggan, based on a true story, 2005 (Folder 10, Box 14)
    - Storm King, by Mary Vance Duggan, based on a true story, undated (Folder 11, Box 14)
    - Untitled screenplay, likely In the Public Interest, by Mary Vance Duggan, 2005 (Folder 12, Box 14)
    - CD labeled Public Interest, 2004 March 4 (Folder 13, Box 14)
    - Unlabeled CD, 2004 March 5 (Folder 14, Box 14)
  - Genealogical Research, 7.2; Box: 15 Folders: 1-4
    - Genealogical research, 2009 (Folder 1, Box 15)
    - Genealogical research, undated (Folder 2, Box 15)
    - Genealogical research, undated (Folder 3, Box 15)
    - Genealogical research, undated (Folder 4, Box 15)
  - Collected Research by Mary Vance Duggan, 1999 - 2004; 7.3; Box: 15 Folders: 5 - 10
    - Collected research, 1999 (Folder 5, Box 15)
    - Envelope that contained collected research, 2004 (Folder 6, Box 15)
    - Collected research, 2004 (Folder 7, Box 15)
    - Collected research, 2004 (Folder 8, Box 15)
    - Collected research, 2004 (Folder 9, Box 15)
    - Collected research, 2004 (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - Character Research, 2002 - 2008; 7.4; Box: 15 Folders: 11 - 18
    - Character research, 2002 (Folder 11, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2003 (Folder 12, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2004 (Folder 13, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2004 (Folder 14, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2006 (Folder 15, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2008 (Folder 16, Box 15)
    - Character research, 2008 (Folder 17, Box 15)
    - Character research, undated (Folder 18, Box 15)
  - Writing Notes and Drafts, 7.5; Box: 15 Folders: 19 - 28
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 19, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 20, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 21, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 22, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 23, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 24, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 25, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 26, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 27, Box 15)
    - Writing notes and drafts, undated (Folder 28, Box 15)